

Languages

English - Advanced Spanish - Native

Skills

Hard

Traira
ReactJS NextJS Storybook Design Systems
HTML5 CSS3 Typescript Styled Components
Framer Motion React Spring Git Github
Microinteractions Responsive Cross Browsing
AllY Figma

Soft

30][
Communication	Teamwork	Social Skills
Taking Criticism	Proactivity	Creativity
Collaboration	Organization	Problem Solving

Education

- MERN Fullstack Bootcamp @FullstackOpen
- React: The complete guide @Udemy
- Google Analytics & SEO @GeekBoss
- Git & Github @Platzi
- User Experience & User Interface Design @Platzi
- Web Development @Platzi
- Multimedia Production Technology @SENA

▼ Social





About Me

I'm a passionate, proactive, with keen eye for details, Frontend Developer focused on UI UX and interactions with 8 years of experience. My passion is to build and maintain websites and applications in NextJS / ReactJS and Storybook, working together with design and development teams.

In my free time I like to study 📽 and play videogames 🙀.

Experience



UX UI Developer / Web Designer @Freelance January 2013 - Today

I help companies and startups develop and maintain websites and design system components in ReactJS and Storybook. I build the application layouts, make it responsive and improve the user experience and user interface. In some cases I provide a full service by creating the designs as well.



Frontend Developer @LePolishBureau November 2021 - Today

Working for a Polish company building amazing award winning websites and applications. I help to build the frontend components using React, StoryBook and Framer Motion for interactions.



SSR UX Developer @MakingSense January 2021 - October 2021

I work 100% remotely with an Argentinian and USA team on a large-scale app for the agricultural sector. Some of my duties are to mantain the entire design system built with ReactJS and Storybook, add new components based on designs, refactor old code moving from JS classes to hooks and Typescript, SASS to Styled Components and improve responsiveness.



UX UI Developer @10Pearls
September 2019 - December 2020

I built the entire UI library in ReactJS for an educational public project. I had to keep the constant communication with the designers and product managers from the USA team to deliver the best product possible. I also communicated with the frontend team to deliver easy to use, scalable and mantainable components. I improved the UX by adding extra UI functionalities like Skeleton loading.



UX UI Developer @Integ.ro July 2018 - September 2019

I was, from start to finish, building an entire website for a prestigious university from my city. The client would send us the designs and I would bring it to life by coding it on WordPress. One of the biggest challenges was to make it fully accesible, so I had to research a lot and learn about ally implementation, testing and debugging.



Web Lead @Interficto September 2015 - June 2018

My main task in this company was to make cool and goal centered websites in WordPress using templates with code modifications. My job position here was about communication with the company clients, cleaning WordPress virus from client websites, hosting maintenance, design and web development, team and client capacitations, sending mailchimp campaigns and many other tasks.



Production Director @Sigital January 2013 - June 2015

In this company I started as a web developer, then I was promoted to project manager and finally I worked as a production manager. A lot of teamwork here. My job was to watch the design and development area of the company. I used WordPress as CMS, documentation and process optimization, suppliers management, QA, website optimization to achieve goals and generate conversions and research of platforms to improve processes. Web design in overtime for projects.

Portfolio







Recommendations



Emily Biondo @10Pearls UX UI Design Lead

Alejandro is amazing at his job. He has an intuitive sensibility for UX and UI, and is a fantastic collaborator. Working with him was effortless—he was always responsive, always confident we could arrive at a solution, and always came through with effective, beautiful interfaces. I wish I could work with a thousand Alejandros.



Dylan Donlon-Moyer @10Pearls Product Delivery Manager

Alejandro is an incredible UI/UX talent and an absolutely wonderful colleague to work with. He is responsive, friendly, and efficient in his duties, and is always eager to continue learning and improving the products he creates. He faithfully brings even the most complex designs to life and can always be counted on to build reliable and beautiful frameworks for any project. I would love to have Alejandro on all of my teams!



Liliana Franco (aInteg.ro Scrum Master

Are you looking for a good team player? Then Alejo is definitely the right match. He is a great UI designer with a keen eye for details. He is always ready to help the team, ready to learn new things and ready for challenges. I worked with him for about one year and I would definitely repeat the experience.

Not convinced yet? Let's talk *